Guide to the Alfred Stieglitz / Georgia O'Keeffe Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Alfred Stieglitz / Georgia O'Keeffe collection
1893-2013
YCAL MSS 104
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.2
(1 box)
The Alfred Stieglitz/Georgia O'Keeffe Collection contains items acquired by the Beinecke Library after 1980. Previous accessions are part of the Alfred Stieglitz/Georgia O'Keeffe Archive [YCAL MSS 85]
Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946
O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources, to supplement the Stieglitz/O'Keeffe Archive (YCAL MSS 85). Type of accession (gift or purchase) and date of acquisition is noted in the box-and-folder list. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Alfred Stieglitz / Georgia O'Keeffe Archive [YCAL MSS 85] and Flora Stieglitz Straus Collection of Stieglitz Family Papers [YCAL MSS 89]
ALFRED STIEGLITZ AND GEORGIA O'KEEFFE
Biographical statements can be found in the finding aid for the Alfred Stieglitz / Georgia O'Keeffe Archive [YCAL MSS 85].
Scope and Contents
This collection gathers items related to Stieglitz and O'Keeffe which were acquired by the Beinecke Library after 1980. Earlier accessions are listed in the Alfred Stieglitz / Georgia O'Keeffe Archive [YCAL MSS 85]. Materials incorporated into the collection prior to June 1997 have been organized into one series: Correspondence. Materials added to the collection since that time are located in Series II, Additions since June 1997, listed in the order in which they were added.
Photographers -- United States; Photography, Artistic -- History; Photographers; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946
- Correspondence, Series I
  - ALFRED STIEGLITZ
    - Letter: Lake George, to Alice Benedict 1 item (1 p.); 28 cm., 1938 Aug 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      ALS sending greetings.
      Gift, 1984.
    - Letter: to Mr. [Ananda Kentish] Coomaraswamy, 1923 Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      1 item (1 p.); 28 cm.
      ALS regarding their previous meeting.
      Purchase, 1997.
    - Letter: Lake George, to A[nanda Kentish] C[oomaraswamy], [19]24 Aug 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      1 item (2 p.); 28 cm.
      ALS regarding Eastman's postal card
      paper.
    - Letters: to Wilhelm Hasemann 3 items (8 p.), 1893, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      3 ALS describing work and plans
      to visit Hasemann in Gutach.
      In German.
      Accompanied by 2 photographs:
      1 of Agnes Stieglitz Engelhard
      (sister of AS), ca. 1884 and
      group of children with elderly woman,
      1923; along with postcard of Wilhelm
      Hasemann and printed material about
      Hasemann and Gutach, his home town in
      Germany.
      Gift, 1987.
    - Letter: Lake George, to Mrs. Jackson 1 item (2 p.); 28 cm., 1940 Sep 10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      ALS thanking her for a visit.
    - Letter: to Robert Josephy 1 item (2 p.); 28 cm., 1934 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      ALS thanking him for a book and
      describing his involvement with
      The New School.
      Gift, 1994.
    - Letters: to Doris Klingelhofer 5 items (5 p.), 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      5 ALS encouraging the young writer.
      Purchase, 1982.
    - Letters: to Guy Metraux 6 items (10 p.), 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      3 ALS and 3 TLS following up on a
      conversation about photographic
      portraits of AS.
      Accompanied by 1 ALS from William
      Lyon Phelps to Guy Metraux, and a
      note by P. R. Metraux.
      With: 5 envelopes.
      1 of the TLS is a duplicate.
      Purchase, 1987.
    - Letters: to James Henry Moser 6 items (29 p.), 1904-06 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      6 ALS concerning the establishment
      of the Photo-Secession and the
      progress of Camera Work.
      Includes: photocopies page from
      biographical dictionary with entry
      on Moser.
      Purchase, 1984.
- Additions since June 1997, Series II
  - CLIPPINGS
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1960 Oct 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Schubart, Selma Stieglitz, 1957 Jun 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Stieglitz, Julius, 1917-44 (Box 1, Folder 12)